Sail the high seas. Battle the pirates. Live the adventure.
Treasure Island is a adventure, family, tv movie
film directed by Fraser Clarke Heston.
Young Jim Hawkins, while running the Benbow Inn with his mother, meets Captain Billy Bones,
who dies at the inn while it is beseiged by buccaneers led by Blind Pew.
Jim and his mother fight off the attackers and discover Billy
Bones' treasure map for which the buccaneers had come.
Jim agrees to sail on the S.S.
Espaniola with Squire Trelawney and Dr.
Livesey to find the treasure on a mysterious isiand.
Upon arriving at the island, ship's cook and scaliwag Long John Silver leads a
mutiny of crew members who want the treasure for themselves.
Jim helps the Squire and Espaniola officers to survive the mutiny and fight
back against Silver's men, who have taken over the Espaniola.
Long John Silver, played by Charlton Heston.
Jim Hawkins, played by Christian Bale.
Billy Bones, played by Oliver Reed.
Blind Pew, played by Christopher Lee.
Squire Trelawney, played by Richard Johnson.
Dr. Livesey, played by Julian Glover.
Treasure Island is a 1990 British-American made-for-television film adaptation of Robert Louis Stevenson’s 1883 novel of the same name, written and directed by Fraser
Clarke Heston and starring several notable British actors, including Christian Bale, Oliver Reed, Christopher Lee, Julian Glover and Pete Postlethwaite.
The film was an original production filmed and aired by the TNT
network, and was also released theatrically outside the US.
The title has appeared on some covers as Devils
Treasure, rather than Treasure Island.
This version of the story is noted for its faithfulness to the book, with much of the dialogue coming
directly from it, as well as recreating several of the more violent scenes from the book.
The film explores themes of ship, treasure, mutiny, island, treasure hunt.